哈喽大家好
Hello everyone,
今天上午我跟拐哥 就是“拐哥打野”
This morning "Guai Ge" (from Guai Ge Da Ye) and I
取了两个蜂窝
went to harvest two wasps hives
这个有十多斤
This one is about 10 lbs
这个可能有五六斤
This one is about 5-6 lbs
然后现在把它拿回来
Now, we've brought them back
拐哥因为他经常会有这些东西
Brother Guai has lots of them
所以今天他把这两个给我了
so he gave these to me today
现在我们把它处理一下
Now, let's prepare them
在我伯爷家
we are at my uncle's place
大家一起尝一下鲜
Let's try this new dish together
这个东西放出来才凶哦
The wasps are aggressive when they are out
嘿嘿 放出来还得了啊
haha, it will be disastrous if we let them out
那样就是放蜂子
that would be setting the wasps to go away on their own
嘿嘿嘿
[laughter]
不要拿手去摸屁股一下就蛰到你了
don't touch it, you might get stung in the butt
看嘛 它在找
look, they are looking for opening
这个黑蜂子那天在我这里
there was a wasp
就是打屋檐口那天
on the day of...
就蛰了我一下
it stung me
我拿手去摸就跑了
it flew away as soon as I touched it
这里还有一个疤疤
but the sting left a scar here
是啊 打屋檐门口混凝土的时候
yeah, on the day when we...
我看看
let me take a look
哎呀 肿没肿哦
it's not swollen
当时肯定肿了
it was swollen when I just got stung
这里烂都烂（坏死）了
the skin here looks dead
后来我拿蛇药（抹）
Then I applied medicine on the area
蛇咬到的药抹了三四次
???? I applied three to four times
它居然敢咬你啊
can't believe it had the guts to sting you
你是“火云邪神”哒
You are "Huo Yun Xie Shen"
哈哈哈
[laughter]
这个怎么整来吃啊
So how are we going to cook these
这蜂子啊
The wasps?
啊
yeah
这个蜂子等会用水淹死
We will drown the wasps in water first
不是不敢碰它 他咬着你不得了
we can't tough them now, they will sting you
淹死了又怎么整啊
what do we do after the wasps are drown?
淹死了大蜂子也可以炸来吃
the more developed wasps (pupae) can be fried
小蜂子弄来蒸
the under-developed wasps (larvae) can be steamed first,
整了过后再把它抖出来
picked and sieved out afterwards,
抖出来了再用油煎哈煎哈就可以吃了
fried with oil at last
油煎来不好吃 硬是要用油来炸 炸起来才好吃
stir-fry doesn't taste as good as deep fry
扎焦
fry to burnt
我就是害怕你说我用你的宽油了
I was afraid you would say "Kuan You"???
哈哈哈
[laughter]
没得事管他宽油不宽油
Don't worry about using too much oil
不存在的噶
For you, there's no such thing as too much oil
不存在
yep, no such thing
要得 我先拿去把它淹死
alright, I'll go ahead and drown these first
在那个水缸里淹
in the water tank over there
先把这个拍烂了才淹它
we need to break it all up before putting it in the water
都还没有死 它比人都还更能憋气
They are not dead yet. They can hold longer breaths than human
千万不要松手
Do not let go
假如现在去碰它会不会被蛰到
If we put our hand in, would we get stung?
百分之百蛰到
100% it will sting you
你害不害怕这个
Are you scared?
不害怕
I am not scared.
平时看到这种蜜（马）蜂要躲开知道吗
Stay away if a wasp approaches you, okay?
嗯
Okay.
因为它会咬人
Because they "bite" (sting) people.
会蛰人
Sting people.
对 会蛰人
Yes, sting people.
嘿嘿嘿
[laughter]
爸爸 我喜欢吃这个白色的
Daddy, I like eating the white stuff.
等下爸爸做给你吃好不好
I will cook it for you later, okay?
好不好啊
Is that okay?
好
Okay.
必须先把这个大的蜜蜂处理好了
We need to deal with the more developed wasps first,
然后再处理这个蜂蛹
before we can deal with the larvae
大家可以看一下 这个黑色的全部都是
You see, all the black are
蜜蜂
wasps.
而且这个绝对没有死的
And they are definitely still alive
直接掰开来抖
Crack it open and shake
嘿嘿
[laughter]
真的啊
For real.
那里有一个在动
There's one still moving.
夹起来夹起来
Pick it up. Over there.
拿水来透一下
Rinse it with water.
小二娃弄点水来
Get some water over here.
要不要拿簸箕
Do you need sifter?
要拿簸箕
yeah, need sifter.
你看这个就是蜜蜂（马蜂）
Look, this is a wasp.
看到没
Do you see it?
我不敢吃这个
I am afraid to eat this.
我只敢吃
I can only eat this (larvae).
只敢吃白色的对不对？
The white ones, right?
我不敢吃这个
I am afraid to eat this.
我只敢吃这个
I can only eat this.
你敢吃哪一个呀？
Which one are you not afraid to eat?
我只敢吃白色的
I am not afraid to eat the white ones.
黑色的很吓人对不对
The black ones look scary, right?
黑色的我也敢吃
I can eat the black ones too.
是吗？
Is that right?
嗯
Yes.
好勇敢啊
So brave.
哇
Wow.
这一瓶油全部倒下去哦
I will pour the entire bottle in.
随便你
It's up to you.
嘿嘿 宽油哦
haha, Kuan You (?)
这个菜籽油这么香 是不是上次我们自己整的哦
This bottle of rapeseed oils smells really good. Didn't we make it?
就是上次在八挑（地名）
Yeah, at Ba Tiao (place)
打的菜籽晒干了拿去炸的
we harvested the rapeseeds and deep-fried them
真的香诶
It smells really good.
我们这个四川的菜籽油就是一定要烧到
The rapeseed oil has to be cooked
烧到没有泡泡
until there are no more foamy bubbles
才会更香
It is more fragrant that way
如果这个泡子还在的话就说明这个油是生油
The presence of foamy bubbles means the oil is uncooked
一定要烧到熟为止
We have to cook it thoroughly
而且炸这个蜂蛹油温要高
Plus, frying these larvae requires the oil to be very hot.
这个油比较少
We have less oil,
这个蜂蛹比较多
more larvae.
下去之后又不能炸太久
Once submerged, larvae cannot stay in the oil for too long.
炸过头了这个是苦的
Over frying can cause bitterness,
又不香
less fragrant
所以这个很考验火候跟油温
So reaching the correct temperature in both heat and oil is a big challenge
但是抓蜂子这个事情不建议大家去尝试
By the way, I do not recommend anyone to harvest wasp hives
请勿模仿
Please do not copy.
这个是我专门带过来的
I brought this here specifically for this purpose
炸酥肉这些
For deep-frying meat and stuff.
就可以用
You can use this.
是
Exactly.
现在油温已经到位了
Now the oil has reached the right temperature
我们把这个放进去
Let's put this in
小心哦四伯 这个多凶的哟
Watch out for the splashing
这个油本来就是拿来吃的
This oil is for food purpose.
管得你宽不宽油哦随便你放
You can put as much oil as you like.
你随心所欲
As much as you like.
真的吗
Really?
要的嘛
Of course.
有你这句话就好办
That's easy then.
我就说了这句话你就放心了
That's why I said it.
我就好
That's good to know.
我就好真的随心所欲地用了
I can put as much as I want then.
还没炸上颜色
The color is not ready.
还差一点点
It's very close to done
马上要好了
It's almost done.
好我肯定晓得早就好了
I would know when it's done.
这个口感要到位
the texture needs to be right
想吃吗，老婆？
Want to try, honey?
好香
It smells really good.
颜色到位没有？
Is the color ready yet?
颜色还没到位
Not yet.
嗯 香了
Yeah, it smells really good now.
四伯爷 香了
好了就捞起来撒 火（要）退了吗？
Take it out once it's done. Is the fire out?
火就退了嘛
The fire is out.
准备吃了
It's ready to be served.
金黄金黄的
Golden brown color.
这个好了之后放一点盐
Sprinkle some salt
这样子撒
Like this
喂你一个
Here take one.
再喂你两个
Here take two.
喂妈妈一个
Give one to mama too.
已经喂了妈妈两个了
I've already given mama two pieces.
再喂一个嘛
Give her another piece.
两个
two larvae!
三个呀
three larvae..
我也喂你一个
I'll feed you one too.
你不喂我一个呀？
Why aren't you feeding me?
你不喂爷爷一个吗？
Aren't you going to give Papa one too?
再喂爷爷一个
Give one to Papa too.
嗯 真乖宝贝
What a good girl.